Mss.B.J35
American Philosophical Society
The later documents are an assortment of letters dealing with American Philosophical Society affairs, science, and engineering. It includes a long letter from Jonathan Williams that deals with a dispute between William Temple Franklin and the APS, and a long letter from Robert Fulton to Thomas Jefferson that includes sketches of a weapon that fires weapons underwater.
The collections contains correspondence from France when Jefferson served as the emissary to the nation during the late-Confederation period. These and some of the documents from the Washington administration contain discussions of politics. There is a particularly rich series of letters from 1798 on early republican politics.
A large portion of the revolutionary era documents were not written by or addressed to Jefferson. Instead, they contain other sources that chronicle the political history of Virginia during the Revolution, especially for the years 1775-1776. This includes speeches and letters from Lord Dunmore, and petitions, speeches, and letters of Virginians, and official government proceedings and documents. It is likely these were compiled by Jefferson to help L.H. Giardin write a history of Virginia, as one of the letters has a handwritten header “a specimen of the spirit which animated Virginia in 1775.”
There are only a few letters from presidential years, most notably a speech delivered to the Miami and Delaware Indians in 1803. Some of the earliest correspondence between Thomas Jefferson and Robert Patterson dates to Jefferson second term as President and discusses matters of state, with one letter inviting Patterson to be the Director of the Mint. The later documents to Patterson chronicle Jefferson’s pursuits in natural history.
There is, however, a significant amount of retirement correspondence, some of which chronicles Jefferson’s involvement in science and technology, including a plan for the Virginia Agricultural Society.
A letter to Matthew Carey on religion in which he discusses his refusal to comment on his views publicly, significant correspondence with David Rittenhouse from 1790s in Philadelphia, a passport for Rembrandt Peale with a letter to Charles Willson Peale are among the other noteworthy pieces of correspondence.
American Philosophical Society.; Bache, Franklin, 1792-1864; Byrd, William, 1674-1744; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844; Eppes, John Wayles, 1773-1823; Fleming, William, 1729-1795; Fulton, Robert, 1765-1815; Girardin, Louis Hue, 1771-1825; Ingenhousz, Jan, 1730-1799; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794; Mease, James, 1771-1846; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813; Thornton, William, 1759-1828; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841; Washington, Bushrod, 1762-1829; Washington, George, 1732-1799; Williams, Jonathan.; Wistar, Caspar, 1761-1818; American Revolution; Boundaries, State.; Canals.; Chemistry; Colony and State Specific History; Diplomatic History; Early National Politics; General Correspondence; Government Affairs; Indians of North America--Languages; Linguistics.; Louisiana Purchase -- Enclopedias.; Native America; Natural History; Official Government Documents and Records; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Social life and customs.; Plants.; Political Correspondence; Presidents -- United States.; Science -- United States -- 18th century.; Science and Technology; Scientific apparatus and instruments.; Seeds.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1775-1783 -- Anecdotes, facetiae, satire, etc.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1783-1865.; Virginia -- History.
- Thomas Jefferson collection, 1791-1840; B J35Le; 63.0 Item(s); Letters to and from various persons, including L.H. Girardin, Correa de Serra, Alexander Humboldt, Caspar Wistar, Peter Stephen Duponceau, et al.; 63 items.; Corrêa da Serra, Edward J.; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844; Girardin, Louis Hue, 1771-1825; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Wistar, Caspar, 1761-1818
  - Thomas Jefferson to John Stuart, November 10, 1796., 1769 November 10
  - Land surrounding R. Carter's Patent for 400 acres, 1790 October 17; 1 map, 20.3 x 30.5 cm; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Scope and Contents note
    Annotation: "The line which divides Rob. Carter's 400 a[cre]s between Mr. [John] Wayles and Carter H. Harrison (who purchased the moiety) was run by Col. Carrington from Carter and Shelton's corner red oak to Willis' Creek S. 65 W. 272 po."
    Jefferson sold his share of this land, which came to him through his wife, Martha Skelton, to Nicholas Lewis, and the indenture which conveyed the land is with the map.
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 22 (1).
  - Invitation From Thomas Jefferson to David Foster., 1802 February 1; 1.0 Item(s); Invitation for Foster to dine with Jefferson
  - Thomas Jefferson to Benjamin Smith Barton, September 21, 1809., 1809 September 21
  - Thomas Jefferson to [Robert] Patterson, December 19, 1809., 1809 December 19; Letter to Patterson accompanying a paper by Mr. Lambert, to be presented to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Thomas Jefferson to Joseph Nicolson, May 21, 1814., 1814 May 21; Letter from Jefferson thanking Nicolson for the introduction to a Mr. McCulloch, and for Nicolson's defense of the constitution from "those who were rapidly monarchising it."
  - William Lambert to Thomas Jefferson, June 24, 1814, 1814 June 24; Letter from Lambert proposing a topic of inquiry for the American Philosophical Society concerning the accuracy of the Julian calendar, and advocating an additional year be switched from leap year to a common year to fix a problem that will occur 3600 years from the beginning of the calendar.
  - Thomas Jefferson to John Vaughn, March 1, 1815., 1815 March 1; Letter to John Vaughn, relating Jefferson's need to replenish his library after offering his books to the Library of Congress.
  - J. W. Gilmore to John Vaughn, June 16, 1815., 1815 June 16; Letter from J. W. Gilmore to John Vaughn, touching on a number of topics including the purchase of books for Thomas Jefferson.
  - Thomas Jefferson to [John] Vaughn, June 7, 1817., 1817 June 7; Letter to [John] Vaughn, asking for assistance in ordering books from France and investing money.
- Papers
  - Notes for the biography of George Wythe., 1743-1826; B J35.70; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Xerox of A.D. 3p. Emphasizes Wythe's part in the Stamp Act crisis and the Revolutionary War. Presented by Herbert R. Strauss; May 1972.
  - Letter to the House of Burgesses of Virginia, June, [1775]; B J35.51 no.9; 12-3/4x7; Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809
    L. 8p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.9.) Concerning the outbreak of war.
  - Letter to Capt. White-Eyes, [1775]; B J35.51 no.13; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809
    D. 1p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.13.) Wishes peace between Indians and colonists. Not Found: 7/19/2010
  - Speech to Peyton Randolph by the Williamsburg volunteers, and his reply, June 2, [1775]; B J35.51 no.3; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Williamsburg (Va.) Volunteers
    D. 2p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.3.) Concerning his services at the Continental Congress.
  - Oath of allegiance, [1776]; B J35.51 no.25; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Virginia (State)
    D. 1p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.25.)
  - Resolutions calling for independence, May 15, [1776]; B J35.51 no.15; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Virginia. Convention
    D. 1p. Incomplete. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.15.) Printed: Boyd, I, 291.
  - Letter to ----, [1782?]; B J35.51 no. 32; 12-3/4x8; Lee, Henry, 1756-1818
    L. 1p. Extract. Copy. (see T.Jefferson Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.32.) Concerning the war. Concerning Gates. On same sheet as: H.Gates to ----; July 20, 1780.
  - An act authorizing the transfer of its claim to the territory northwest of the Ohio River, February, [1784]; B J35.51 no.34; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Virginia
    D. 3p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.34.) Printed: Boyd, VI, 5771.
  - Letter to [William Howe?], 1775; B J35.51 no.12; 12x7-3/4; Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809
    L. 2p. Incomplete. Copy (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. Concerning the war.
  - Proceedings, March 20- March 27, 1775; B J35.51 no.1; 13x7-3/4; Virginia (Colony). Convention of 1775
    D. 10p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.1.) Refers to B.Franklin, T.Jefferson, etc.
  - Letter to Andrew Lewis and John Boyer, 1775; B J35.51 no.7; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Virginia. Freeholders of Botetourt
    L. 2p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no. 7.) Concerning the sentiments of this part of Virginia at the outbreak of the Revolution.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, April 5, 1775; B J35.51 no.2.; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Wythe, George, 1726-1806
    Williamsburg, L. 1p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.2.) Printed: Boyd, I, 163. On same sheet is letter from same to same; April 7, 1775.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, April 7, 1775; B J35.51 no.2.; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Wythe, George, 1726-1806
    L. 2p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.2.) Printed: Boyd, I, 163-164. On same sheet as same to same; April 5, 1775.
  - Letter to the House of Burgesses of Virginia, June 14, 1775; B J35.51 no.4; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809
    L. 5p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.4.) Printed: Boyd, I, 173ff.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Aug. 12, 1775; B J35.51 no.5; 6-1/4x7-3/4; Tucker, St. George, 1752-1827
    Bermuda, L. 1p. Incomplete. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no. 5.) Printed: Boyd, I, 239.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Nov. 16, 1775; B J35.x3; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
    Caroline, Copy of L. 2p. Military and naval movements. Printed: Boyd, I, 260-261.
  - Letter to William Howe, Nov. 30, 1775; B J35.51 no.6; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809
    L. 4p. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.6.) Concerning the war.
  - Miscellaneous notes of Virginia news concerning the Revolution, [1775]; B J35.51 no.8
  - Correspondence between Lord Dunmore and Robert Howe concerning Norfolk and the war., 1775; B J35.51 no. 10; Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809
  - Patrick Henry to the House of Burgesses., [1775]; B J35.51 no. 11; Henry, Patrick, 1726-1799
    Appointment of officers.
  - Proposals to General Gage for separating the northern and southern governments, 1776; B J35.51 no.26; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Connelly,
    [?]. D. 2p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.26.)
  - Plan of government for Virginia, by Mason and Jefferson, June 8 - June 10, 1776; B J35.51 no.17; 12-3/4x7-1/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    D. 10p. Extract. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.17.) Printed: Boyd, I, 366ff. On same sheet is copy of letter from E. Pendleton to T. Jefferson; Aug.10,1776.
  - Letter to [Thomas] Jefferson, Feb. 4, 1776; B J35.51 no.14; 12-3/4x7-1/2 and 10x7-1/2; Nelson, Thomas, 1738-1789
    Philadelphia, L. 3p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.14.) Printed: Boyd, I, 285-286.
  - Resolution for individual states to form governments, May 15, 1776; B J35.51 no.16; 12-3/4x7-1/2; United States. Continental Congress
    D. 2p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.16.) Printed: Journals of the Continental Congress, IV, 357-358.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson]:, June 15, 1776; B J35.x5; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Fleming, William, 1729-1795
    W[illia]msburg, Copy of L. 2p. Discouraging news from Canada. War with Indians imminent. Declaration of rights to serve as basis of the new government. Bureau of rolls. v.8,186 - S.2,v.33, no.33.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], June 23, 1776; B J35.x8; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    York Copy of L. 1p. Bureau of rolls, v.8,352 - S.2,v.51, no.20. Printed: Ballagh, V.1,418.
  - Resolution, June 24, 1776; B J35.51 no.20; 11-3/4x7-1/2; United States. Continental Congress
    D. 1p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.20.) Defining treason to the colonial cause. On same sheet as copy of letter from G. Wythe to T.Jefferson; July 27, 1776.
  - Letter to --, June 29, 1776; B J35.51 no. 18
  - Declaration of independence, July 4, 1776; B J35.80; United States. Continental Congress.
    Xerox of draft of Declaration.
  - Declaration of independence, July 4, 1776; B J35.81; Deacidified xerox copy of the Declaration of Independence.; United States. Continental Congress.
  - Letter to [Richard Henry Lee], July 8, 1776; B J35.74; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Xerox of copy of L. 1p., enclosures wanting. For original enclosures
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], July 21, 1776; B J35.x7; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    Chantilly Copy of L. 2p. Bureau of rolls,v.8,351 - S.2,v.51, no.12. Printed: Ballagh, v.1,210.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], July 27, 1776; B J35.51 no.19; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Fleming, William, 1729-1795
    Mo[u]nt Pleasant, L. 4p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.19.) Printed: Boyd, I, 474-476.
  - Letter to T[homas] J[efferson], July 27, 1776; B J35.51 no.20; 11-3/4x7-1/2 and 12-3/4x7-1/2; Wythe, George, 1726-1806
    Williamsburg, L. 2p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.20.) Printed: Boyd, I, 476-477. On same sheet is copy of resolution by the continental congress; June 24, 1776.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], July 29, 1776; B J35.x6; 7 3/4" x 10"; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
    Caroline, Copy of L. 2p. Account of the war. Bureau of rolls, v.8,450 - S.2,v.65, no.50.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], August 10, 1776; B J35.x2; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
    Caroline, Copy of L. 4p. Alterations in the original Declaration of independence. The proposed new constitution. Military movements. Bureau of rolls, v.8,450 - S.2,v.65, no.53.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Aug. 10, 1776; B J35.51 no.17; 12-3/4x7-1/4; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
    L. 1p. Extract. Copy (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. Printed: Boyd, I, 489. On same sheet as copy of: Jefferson. Plan of government...;[June 8-10,1776.]
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson;], Aug. 10, 1776; B J35.51 no.21; 9x7-3/4; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
    L. 2p. Incomplete. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no. 21.) Printed: Boyd, I, 488-491.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Aug. 24, 1776; B J35.51 no.22; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Nichols, Robert Carter
    Williamsburg, L. 1p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.22.) Printed: Boyd, I, 502-503.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Nov. 3, 1776; B J35.x10; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    Philadelphia, Copy of L. 4p. Mutilated. Bureau of rolls, v.8,351 - S.2,v.51, no.13. Printed: Ballagh, v.1,222
  - Letter to T[homas] J[efferson], Nov. 11, 1776; B J35.51 no.23; 6-3/4x6-1/4; Wythe, George, 1726-1806
    L. 1p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.23.) Printed: Boyd, I, 597-598.
  - Letter to T[homas] J[efferson], Nov. 18, 1776; B J35.51 no.24; 12-3/4x7-1/4; Wythe, George, 1726-1806
    Philadelphia, L. 2p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.24.) Printed: Boyd, I, 603-604.
  - Letter to Henry Laurens, Feb. 11, 1778; B J35.51 no.27; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Burgoyne, John, 1722-1792
    Cambridge, L. 6p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.27.) Concerning his imprisonment and treatment.
  - Proceedings..., May 4, 1778; B J35.51 no. 28; 12-1/2x8; Virginia (State). General assembly
    D. 2p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no. 28.) Concerning the case of Josiah Philips.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Oct. 5, 1778; B J35.51 no.29; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    Philadelphia, L. 2p. Incomplete. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.29.) Printed: Boyd, II, 214-215.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], March 15, 1779; B J35.x9; 5x7-1/2; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    Philadelphia, Copy of L. 2p. Bureau of rolls, v.8,352 - S.2, v.51, no.23. Printed: Ballagh, v.2,38.
  - Letter to [Patrick Henry], March 27, 1779; B J35.51 no.30; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Albemarle, L. 2p. Incomplete. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no. 30.) Printed: Boyd, II, 237-
  - Letter to Patrick Henry, April 29, 1779; B J35.51 no.31; 13x8; Clark, George Rogers, 1752-1818
    Kaskaskia, L. 5p. Copy. (see T.Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.31.) Printed: Boyd, II, 256-260.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], May 22, 1779; B J35.x4; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Fleming, William, 1729-1795
    Philadelphia, Copy of L. 4p. Desperate condition of country. Need for ratification of confederation. Depredations of the enemy. Bureau of rolls, v.8,186 - S.2,v.33, no.37.
  - Commission to Harry Innes to adjust and settle claims to unpatented lands, in Montgomery and Washington districts, Sept. 29, 1779; B J35.46; 7 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    D.S. 1p. Seal.
  - Letter to ----, July 20, 1780; B J35.51 no.32; 12-3/4x8; Gates, Horatio, 1728-1806
    Hillsborough, L. 1p. Copy. (see T. Jefferson. Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.32.) Concerning the war. Refers to Jefferson. On same sheet is copy of letter from Henry Lee to ---.; [1782].
  - Letter to the president of Congress [Samuel Huntington], Jan. 10, 1781; B J35.14; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Richmond, Copy of L. 3p. Bureau of rolls, v.6,92 - S.1,v.1,no. 68. Printed: Ford, v.2,405
  - Letter to [George Washington], May 28, 1781; B J35.15; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Charlottesville, Copy of L. 2p. Bureau of rolls,v.6,485 - S.1,v.1, no.97. Printed: Ford, v.3,41.
  - Letter to [Charles Thomson?], Dec. 20, 1781; B J35.13; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Richmond Typescript of L. 1p. Has been appointed councillor of the American philosophical society. Queries made by M. de Marbois. Presented by George Vaux, June 1917, cf. covering letter of June 6,1917 to I.Minis Hays in Archives.
  - Concerning Benedict Arnold's raid on Virginia., 1781; B J35.51 no. 33
  - Journals..., March 1, 1784; B J35.51 no.35; 12-1/2x7-3/4; United States. Continental Congress
    D. 2p. Extract. (see T.Jefferson, Correspondence...; 1775-1784. no.35.) Printed: Journals of the continental congress, XXIV, 112.
  - Letter to [Isaac Zane ?], March 17, 1784; B J35.23; 7 1/4" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Annapolis, A.L.S. 1p. and end. News about the British ministry from Dr. Franklin. Deed of cession for the western country. Hopkinson writes about bill before [Pa.] Assembly relative to Rittenhouse.
  - Letter to Mr. Stockdale, Sept. 1, 1784; B J35.41; 9 1/4" x 7 1/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Orders copy of Blackstone. Mr. [William Temple] Franklin is acting as his agent in the purchase of other books. Mr. Franklin may be found at Gov. Franklin's. Not printed in Boyd.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, Passy, Nov. 25, 1784; B J35.53; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Photostat of A.L. in 3rd Person. 1p. and add. (from original in Library of Congress.) Concerning Beaumarchais' demands on Virginia. Presented by Julian Boyd, 1951.
  - Letter to ----, July 5, 1785; B J35.73; 10x7; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, Xerox of A.L.S. 1p. Introduces William Temple Franklin and refers to "his grandfather."
  - Letter to [Francis Hopkinson], July 6, 1785; B J35.35; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, Photo. of A.L.S. 2p. The harpsichord. Dr. Franklin's departure. Mr. Jefferson's Notes. From original in Independence hall. Presented by C.F. Jenkins, 1948.
  - Letter to [Johannes Ingenhousz], July 14, 1785; B J35.52; 9x7; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Thomas Jefferson papers.) Forwards package which B. Franklin left with him.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], July 18, 1785; B J35.x12; Holker, Jean
    Rouen, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. In French. Dr. Franklin left previous day for Le Havre. No information on case of books. From origin al in Harvard college. Presented by C.F. Jenkins, 1948.
  - Letter to ---- ----, Nov. 24, 1785; B J35.10; 7 1/2" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Mentions American prisoners.
  - Letter to Dr. Ingenhausz, July 9, 1787; B J35.9; 7 1/4" x 9"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges letter and pamphlet; offers to forward mail to Dr. Franklin. (Contains fine impression of T.J.'s seal)
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Stamford, Conn., Oct. 13, 1787; B J35.x18; 12-1/2x8-1/2; Bushnell, David, ca. 1742-1824
    Xerox of A.L.S. 2p. (from original in New Haven Colony Historical Society) Printed: APS. Transactions, o.s., IV, 303. Presented by Herbert Ebert (cf.letter of 6/26/68).
  - Letter to Mr. Van Damme, March 21, 1788; B J35.59; 4-1/2x7; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Photo.of A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (from original in Diederich Collection, 139 Di, University of Amsterdam Library.) Hopes Van Damme can locate certain books for him.
  - Letter to Gen. Washington, Dec. 5, 1788; B J35.42; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and end. in Washington's hand. Corrects date of letter sent the day previous. Press copy in L.C.
  - Letter to Benjamin Vaughan, Mar.11, 1789; B J35.33; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Paris, Enlargement print A.L.S. 2p. and add. Cultivation of rice. Has asked for a leave of absence to return to America from April to November. From original in possession of Mrs. Frances Vaughan Finletter,March 1951.
  - Letter to [William Temple] Franklin, July 6, 1790; B J35.67; 5x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in. 3rd P. 1p. Invitation to dine.
  - Indenture of Thomas Jefferson and Nicholas Lewis, October 17, 1790; B J35.7; 8" x 12 1/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    on the one part, and William Ronald, on the other part, for a tract of land in Cumberland county... A.D.S. 3p. and end., also survey - 1p.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Oct. 27, 1790; B J35.x17; 11x8-1/2; Bonne, Rigobert, 1727-1794
    Paris, Photodup. copy of typed transcript. 3p. In French. (from trans. in Jefferson Papers, Princeton: original in Library of Congress) Forwards pamphlet on measures for APS: philosophical basis for his ideal measure. See printed Minutes, p.196.
  - Letter to John Churchman, Nov. 23, 1790?; B J35.21; 7" x 8 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and add. and end. "came to hand 24 Nov. 1790" Encloses letter to Mr. Leroy who will distribute Mr. Churchman's chart and pamphlet [Magnetic atlas]. Bur. of rolls, S.2,v.15,no.67.
  - Letter to [David] Rittenhouse, March 19, 1791; B J35.62; 5x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Rode into the country and couldnot drink tea with him or go to APS meeting where Barton read a paper. Sends drawing paper.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin Bache, April 22, 1791; B J35.54; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Photo.of typed copy of L.in 3rd P. 1p. (see Jefferson papers.) Concerning the Aurora. Presented by J.P.Boyd; March 1961.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, May 16, 1791; B J35.58; 4-1/2x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Jefferson papers.) Forwards an Argand double lamp for use for the APS.
  - Letter to Messrs. Havens & Dering, Dec. 22, 1791; B J35.45; 9 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826